Guide to the Darwin D. Martin Papers, 1883-1982 (inclusive), 1904-1949 (bulk)
Department of Special Collections
Darwin D. Martin Papers,
1883-1982 (inclusive), 1904-1949 (bulk)
Special Collections M0355
Martin, Darwin D.
4 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Partial gift of Jean and Paul Hanna and the Library Associates, 1982 and 1983.
Biographical Note
Active patron and supporter of Frank Lloyd Wright. Secretary of the Larkin Co. of Buffalo, New York.
Scope and Content
Includes more than 200 letters from Wright and over 2,000 letters to Wright from the Martins and other clients in Buffalo. Wright's letters refer to the design and construction of the Larkin building and the Martin homes and discuss his personal life and his philosophy of art and architecture. Also includes several drafts of manuscripts which Wright prepared for publication.
Container List
- Series I: MARTIN FAMILY PERSONAL PAPERS
  - Oct. 5, 1883 - Dec. 18, 1915. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A Trip to California, June - July 1915 by D.D. Martin. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Dec. 20, 1916 - Mar. 9, 1927. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Apr. 1, 1927 - Oct. 8, 1931. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Nov. 2, 1931 - Sept. 5, 1933. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series II: FRANK LLOYD WRIGHT PAPERS
  - Sept. 20, 1888, Feb. 12, 1897. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Oct. 22 - Dec. 10, 1902. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - [1902] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mar. 20 - Dec. 29, 1903. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Barton House Specifications, July 15, 1903. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Barton House Specifications, Oct. 26, 1903. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Jan. 2 - 21, 1904. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - April 29 - July 30, 1904. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Aug. 1 - 25, 1904. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sept. 8 - Oct. 8, 1904. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Oct. 11 - Nov. 25, 1904. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Dec. 7 - 28, 1904. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Marin House Specifications, July 13, 1904. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - [1904] (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Jan. 16 - Mar. 31, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Apr. 15 - May 31, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - June 3 - Sept. 29, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Oct. 2 - Nov. 29, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 28 xeroxes of FLW sketches, blueprints, etc. of the D.D. Martin house in Buffalo, N.Y. 1904-1909. (Folder (M355))
  - Dec. 5 - 30, 1905. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Martin House Specifications, March 5, 1905. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Jan. 2 - Mar. 24, 1906. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Apr. 17 - Dec. 11, 1906. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The New Edifice of Unity Church, June, 1906. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Jan. 4 - Dec. 19, 1907. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Mar. 9 - Dec. 29, 1908. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Aug. 9 - Sept. 16, 1909. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Jan. 2 - Nov. 17, 1910. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Nov. 19 - Dec. 30, 1910. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Jan. 4 - June 17, 1911. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - June 22 - Dec. 27, 1911. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Jan. 24 - Mar. 30, 1912. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Apr. 3 - Dec. 26, 1912. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Jan. 10 - Sept. 17, 1913. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Sept. 19 - Dec. 10, 1913. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Feb. 12 - Oct. 29, 1914. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Mar. 11 - Dec. 10, 1915. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Jan. 1 - June 31, 1916. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - July 11 - Dec. 23, 1916. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Jan. 2 - June 28, 1917. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - July 9 - Dec. 24, 1917. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Feb. 22, 1918. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Jan. 15 - Nov. 1, 1919. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Apr. 28 - Nov. 5, 1920. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Jan. 31, 1921. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - June 27 - Oct. 27, 1922. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Apr. 15 - 30, 1924. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Jan. 2 - Mar. 31, 1925. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Apr. 1 - May 14, 1925. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - May 16 - June 30, 1925. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - July 3 - Aug. 5, 1925. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Sept. 4 - Nov. 21, 1925. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Apr. 15 - June 22, 1926. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - June 24 - July 31, 1926. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Aug. 3 - Oct. 28, 1926. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Nov. 4 - Dec. 30, 1926. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Jan. 3 - Apr. 30, 1927. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - May 2 - June 30, 1927. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - July 9 - Aug. 31, 1927. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Sept. 7 - Oct. 31, 1927. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Nov. 1 - Dec. 28, 1927. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Jan. 3 - Mar. 30, 1928. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Apr. 5 - May 23, 1928. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - June 1 - 23, 1928. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - July 10 - 31, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Aug. 1 - Oct. 27, 1928. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Nov. 1 - 30, 1928. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Dec. 1 - 17, 1928. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - The Hillside Home School of Allied Arts, 1928. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Ms. for Liberty Magazine, [1928?] (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Jan. 2 - 21, 1929. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Feb. 1 - 16, 1929. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Mar. 5 - 29, 1929. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Apr. 2 - 30, 1929. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - May 4 - June 27, 1929. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - July 1 - 29, 1929. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Aug. 1 - 20, 1929. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Aug. 20 - 30, 1929. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Aug. Sept. 4 - Oct. 21, 1929. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Nov. 9 - Dec. 14, 1929. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Jan. 3 - Feb. 25, 1930. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Apr. 12 - May 19, 1930. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - June 2 - July 24, 1930. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Aug. 6 - Dec. 18, 1930. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Jan. 10 - Oct. 7, 1931. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Feb. 6 - Dec. 2, 1932. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Aug. 14 - Oct. 31, 1933. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Booklets,1933. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Mar. 3 - Dec. 31, 1934. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Jan. 2 - July 15, 1935. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Apr. 24, 1936. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Mar. 1 - Dec. 21, 1938. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Mar. 1 - June 30, 1939. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Bill of Sale, 1940. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Nov. 5 - 18, 1941. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Sept. 27, 1942 - May 11, 1948. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Mar. 30, 1949. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - June 12 - Nov. 30, 1967. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Jan. 5, 1968 - Aug. 9, 1978. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 2 photos: FLW and Javanna (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Olgivanna Wright and Javanna (n.d.)